# **Mary Lueder**

Orlando, FL 34747 | 314-973-0437 | mlueder@gmail.com | LinkedIn | GitHub |

#### **FULL STACK DEVELOPER**

Software Developer with more than 12 years of experience as an ecologist and biologist working in animal care and conservation. Pivoted into tech space earning Software Engineering certificate from General Assembly in March 2023, and now seeking an opportunity on an incredible team as a full-stack developer.

#### **TECHNICAL & INTERPERSONAL SKILLS**

Languages: Typescript, SQL, JavaScript, CSS, HTML

Technologies: React, Express.js, Node.js, Mongoose, Sequelize

**Databases and other:** MongoDB, PostgreSQL **Tooling:** Git, GitHub, VS Code, Postman

Other: JSON APIs, RESTful Routing, Google OAuth, JWT Token Auth

**Interpersonal skills:** Improving team function, collaboration across departments and lines of business, written and verbal communication, public speaking, influential leadership skills, creative problem-solving, working well both independently and as part of a team. Recognized as a knowledgeable, passionate, self-starter by

supervisors and peers.

#### **TECHNICAL PROJECTS**

# Animal Trainer Behavior Tracker - <u>Training Tracker</u> - Express, Node, MongoDB, JavaScript, CSS, HTML CRUD app for professional animal trainers January 2023

- Created an app to streamline training programs for animal care teams
- Build functionality to anticipate needs and solve common challenges
- Implemented full CRUD and Google OAuth authentication and authorization

# Wordle-style App - Wordle - HTML, CSS, JavaScript

Clean app with multiple difficulty options, animations, and the option to play repeatedly

December 2022

- Created a sleek app with a smooth, intuitive interface
- Solved common player complaints by allowing replay and selection of difficulty level
- Added animation features and game logic incorporating time delays

# Pyramid Tic-Tac-Toe - TTT - HTML, CSS, JavaScript

A bright and mind-bending take on a programming classic

• Themed game for engaging user experience

December 2022

#### **EXPERIENCE**

# **The Walt Disney Company**

# **Animal Care Professional - Salaried Keeper Tier 2**

Orlando, FL, 06/2016 - 11/2022

- Diverse experience in managing projects, organizing and analyzing data, and implementing training principles
- Member of a dynamic 23-person team that worked to ensure the daily husbandry of 65 different animals
- Lead environmental efforts for my team and department. Expanded recycling and food waste streams to decrease waste, audited and improved recycling setups to increase ease and accuracy of recycling.
- Reviewed grant proposals for international conservation efforts and ensured alignment with Disney Conservation Fund mission values leading to new partnership activation for concerted sustainability work
- Mentored and trained peers in leadership, husbandry, and technical skills
- Screened and assessed potential interview candidates

#### **Animal Care Professional - Salaried Keeper Tier 3**

12/2013 - 06/2016

 Organized events for 15+ people to help improve team cohesiveness and promote effective communication

- Designed and developed complex animal management programs to better align management goals with best scientific practices
- Created learning materials for front-line partners to teach them about the animals and the way we manage them

# **Animal Care Professional - Hourly Keeper**

01/2011 - 12/2013

- Built competency in multiple demanding roles and work locations, including animal care, guest education, and various challenging and safety-critical animal areas
- Developed positive and highly-functional relationships with a wide variety of people
- Collected and analyzed long-term behavioral data into visual reports to identify patterns in behavior

# **EDUCATION**

**General Assembly** 

Remote, Certificate Expected: 03/2023

Full-stack software engineering 420+ hour program focused on product development fundamentals, object-oriented programming, MVC frameworks, data modeling, and team collaboration strategies.

**University of California San Diego** 

Certificate Earned: 05/2020

Specialized Certificate in Sustainability & Behavior Change

Washington University in St. Louis

St. Louis, MO, Graduated: 05/2010

Bachelor of Arts in Environmental Studies